<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Alda, Sascha</author><author>Cremers, Armin B</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Strategies for a Component-Based Self-adaptability Model in Peer-to-Peer Architectures</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>59-67</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Alda, Cremers - 2004 - Strategies for a Component-Based Self-adaptability Model in Peer-to-Peer Architectures(4).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Department for Applied Computer Science;Europe;Germany;University;University of Bonn</label><abstract>Current peer-to-peer architectures are hardly resistant against unan- ticipated exceptions such as the failure of single peers. This can be justified by the absence of sophisticated models for exception detection and resolution in peer-to-peer architectures. On the other hand, existing generic models for such self-adaptable architectures are rather theoretical and less suitable for the usage by end-users. In this work, strategies for a new self-adaptability model in peer- to-peer architecture are presented incorporating the component technology as the conceptual foundation. The claim of this approach is that through the intui- tive nature of the component technology the process of self-adaptability be- comes more applicable and more comprehendible even for less experienced end- users.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Becker, Steffen</author><author>Overhage, Sven</author><author>Reussner, Ralf H</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Classifying Software Component Interoperability Errors to Support Component Adaption</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>68-83</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Becker, Overhage, Reussner - 2004 - Classifying Software Component Interoperability Errors to Support Component Adaption(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Dept. of Software Engineering and Business Informa;Europe;Germany;Software Engineering Group;University;University of Oldenburg</label><abstract>This paper discusses various classifications of component interoper- ability errors. These classifications aim at supporting the automation of component adaptation. The use of software components will only demonstrate beneficial, if the costs for component deployment (i.e., acquisition and composition) are con- siderably lower than those for custom component development. One of the main reasons for the moderate progress in component-based software engineering are the high costs for component deployment. These costs are mainly caused by adapt- ing components to bridge interoperability errors between unfitting components. One way to lower the costs of component deployment is to support component adaptation by tools, i.e., for interoperability checks of (semi-)automated adaptor generation. This automation of component adaptation requires a deep understand- ing of component interoperability errors. In particular, one has to differentiate between different classes of interoperability errors, as different errors require dif- ferent adaptors for resolving. Therefore, the presented classification of component interoperability errors supports the automation of component adaptation by aiding automated interoperability problem detection and semi-automated adaptor gener- ation. The experience gained from already implemented solutions for a specific class of interoperability errors provides hints for the solution of similar problems of the same class.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bertolino, Antonia</author><author>Mirandola, Raffaela</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>CB-SPE Tool: Putting Component-Based Performance Engineering into Practice</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>233-248</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Bertolino, Mirandola - 2004 - CB-SPE Tool Putting Component-Based Performance Engineering into Practice.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>CNR;Dip. Informatica;Europe;Insitute;Institute;Istituto di Scienza e Tecnologie dell'Informazione;Italy;Sistemi e Produzione;University;Università di Roma “Tor Vergata”</label><abstract>A crucial issue in the design of Component-Based (CB) applications is the ability to early guarantee that the system under development will satisfy its Quality of Service requirements. In particular, we need rigorous and easy-to- use techniques for predicting and analyzing the performance of the assembly based on the properties of the constituent components. To this purpose, we pro- pose the CB-SPE framework: a compositional methodology for CB Software Performance Engineering (SPE) and its supporting tool. CB-SPE is based on, and adapts to a CB paradigm, the concepts and steps of the well-known SPE technology, using for input modeling the standard RT-UML PA profile. The methodology is compositional: it is first applied by the component developer at the component layer, achieving a parametric performance evaluation of the components in isolation; then, at the application layer, the system assembler is provided with a step-wise procedure for predicting the performance of the as- sembled components on the actual platform. We have developed the CB-SPE tool reusing as much as possible existing free tools. In this paper we present the realized framework, together with a simple application example.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bruneton, Eric</author><author>Coupaye, Thierry</author><author>Leclercq, Matthieu</author><author>Quema, Vivien</author><author>Stefani, Jean-bernard</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>An Open Component Model and Its Support in Java</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>7-22</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Bruneton et al. - 2004 - An Open Component Model and Its Support in Java(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;France;France Telecom R&amp;D;INRIA Rhone-Alpes;Insitute;Private Company</label><abstract>This paper presents Fractal, a hierarchical and reflective component model with sharing. Components in this model can be en- dowed with arbitrary reflective capabilities, from black-boxes to compo- nents that allow a fine-grained manipulation of their internal structure. The paper describes Julia, a Java implementation of the model, a small but efficient run-time framework, which relies on a combination of in- terceptors and mixins for the programming of reflective features of com- ponents. The paper presents a qualitative and quantitative evaluation of this implementation, showing that component-based programming in Fractal can be made very efficien</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cervantes, Humberto</author><author>Hall, Richard S</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A Framework for Constructing Adaptive Component- Based Applications : Concepts and Experiences</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>130-137</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cervantes, Hall - 2004 - A Framework for Constructing Adaptive Component- Based Applications Concepts and Experiences.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>220 rue de la Chimie;Domaine Universitaire;Europe;France;Insitute;Laboratoire LSR-IMAG;University</label><abstract>This paper describes the experience of building component-oriented applications with a framework that supports run-time adaptation in response to the dynamic availability of functionality provided by constituent components. The framework’s approach is to define a service-oriented component model, which is a component model that includes concepts from service orientation and an execution environment that provides automatic adaptation mechanisms. This paper focuses on an example scenario and two real-world examples where this framework has been used.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Defour, Olivier</author><author>Jézéquel, Jean-marc</author><author>Plouzeau, Noël</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Extra-Functional Contract Support in Components</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>217-232</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Defour, Jézéquel, Plouzeau - 2004 - Extra-Functional Contract Support in Components(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Avenue du général Leclerc;Campus universitaire de Beaulieu;Europe;France;INRIA-Rennes;University</label><abstract>According to Szyperski, “a software component is a unit of composi- tion with contractually specified interfaces and explicit context dependencies only”. But it is well known that these contractually specified interfaces should go well beyond mere syntactic aspects: they should also involve functional, syn- chronization and Quality of Service (QoS) aspects. In large, mission-critical component based systems, it is also particularly important to be able to explic- itly relate the QoS contracts attached to provided interfaces with the QoS con- tracts obtained from required interfaces. In this paper we propose a language called QoSCL (defined as an add-on to the UML2.0 component model) to let the designer explicitly describe and manipulate these higher level contracts and their dependencies. We show how the very same QoSCL contracts can then be exploited for (1) validation of individual components, by automatically weaving contract monitoring code into the components; and (2) validation of a compo- nent assembly, including getting end-to-end QoS information inferred from in- dividual component contracts, by automatic translation to a Constraint Logic Programming language. We illustrate our approach with the example of a GPS (Global Positioning System) software component, from its functional and con- tractual specifications to its implementation in a .Net framework.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eskenazi, Evgeni</author><author>Fioukov, Alexandre</author><author>Hammer, Dieter</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Performance Prediction for Component Compositions</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>280-293</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Eskenazi, Fioukov, Hammer - 2004 - Performance Prediction for Component Compositions(3).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Department of Mathematics and Computing Science;Europe;Technical University of Eindhoven;The Netherlands;University</label><abstract>A stepwise approach is proposed to predict the performance of com- ponent compositions. The approach considers the major factors influencing the performance of component compositions in sequence: component operations, activities, and composition of activities. During each step, various models – ana- lytical, statistical, simulation − can be constructed to specify the contribution of each relevant factor to the performance of the composition. The architects can flexibly choose which model they use at each step in order to trade prediction accuracy against prediction effort. The approach is illustrated with an example about the performance prediction for an Automobile Navigation System</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Heineman, George T</author><author>Loyall, Joseph</author><author>Schantz, Richard</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Component Technology and QoS Management</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>249-263</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Heineman, Loyall, Schantz - 2004 - Component Technology and QoS Management(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>BBN Technologies;Cambridge;North America;USA;University</label><abstract>Component-based technologies make it possible to decom- pose complex software systems into functional software components. Unfortunately, most component technology does little to address non- functional Quality of Service (QoS) requirements that concern the run- time execution of the software. We are developing a technique to enable one to satisfy QoS requirements of software systems by decomposing and assembling Qoskets similar to the way systems are decomposed into functional components. A qosket is a packaged unit of reusable QoS-related behavior and policy. These qoskets are integrated into a component-based application to enable dynamic, adaptive QoS manage- ment.We present our design and describe our initial prototype.We con- clude with a set of open questions and directions for future work.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jonkers, Hans</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Interface Specification : A Balancing Act</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>5-6</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Jonkers - 2004 - Interface Specification A Balancing Act ( Extended Abstract ).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;Insitute;Philips Research Laboratories Eindhoven;The Netherlands</label></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kotonya, Gerald</author><author>Hutchinson, John</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Viewpoints for Specifying Component-Based Systems</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>114-121</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Kotonya, Hutchinson - 2004 - Viewpoints for Specifying Component-Based Systems(4).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Computing Department;Europe;Lancaster;Lancaster University;United Kingdom;University</label><abstract>There is a conceptual gap between the way we currently articulate requirements and the reuse-driven paradigm embodied in component-based sys- tem development. The principal challenge in requirements engineering for component-based systems is to develop models and methods that allow us make the best use of the available component technology by balancing aspects of re- quirements and business concerns, with the architectural assumptions and capa- bilities embodied in blackbox software components. This paper proposes a method for requirements engineering based on the notion of viewpoints that provides an explicit framework for expressing component-based system re- quirements from initial formulation through to detailed specification.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kulkarni, Sandeep S</author><author>Biyani, Karun N</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Correctness of Component-Based Adaptation</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>48-58</pages><keywords><keyword>Correctness</keyword><keyword>Dynamic Adaptation</keyword><keyword>Verification</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Kulkarni, Biyani - 2004 - Correctness of Component-Based Adaptation(4).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>North America;Software Engineering and Network Systems (SENS) La;USA;University</label><abstract>Long running applications often need to adapt due to chang- ing requirements or changing environment. Typically, such adaptation is performed by dynamically adding or removing components. In these types of adaptation, components are often added to or removed from multiple processes in the system. While techniques for such adaptations have been extensively discussed in the literature, there is a lack of sys- tematic methods to ensure the correctness of dynamic adaptation. To redress this deficiency, in this paper, we propose a new method, based on the concept of proof lattice, for verifying correctness of dynamic adap- tation in a distributed application. We use transitional-invariant lattice to verify correctness of adaptation. As an illustration of this method, we show how correctness of dynamic adaptation is obtained in the context of a message communication application.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lipari, Giuseppe</author><author>Gai, Paolo</author><author>Trimarchi, Michael</author><author>Guidi, Giacomo</author><author>Ancilotti, Paolo</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A Hierarchical Framework for Component-Based Real-Time Systems</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>209-216</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Lipari et al. - 2004 - A Hierarchical Framework for Component-Based Real-Time Systems(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;Italy;Scuola Superiore S. Anna Pisa;University</label><abstract>In this paper, we describe a methodology for the design and the development of component-based real-time systems. In our model, a component consists of a set of concurrent real-time threads that can communicate by means of synchronized operations. In addition, each component can specify its own local scheduling algorithm.We also discuss the support that must be provided at the operating system level, and present an implementation in the SHaRK operating system</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Loecher, Sten</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Model-Based Transaction Service Configuration for Component-Based Development</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>302-309</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Loecher - 2004 - Model-Based Transaction Service Configuration for Component-Based Development(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Dresden University of Technology Department of Com;Europe;Germany;University</label><abstract>An important part of the software engineering process in today’s com- ponent technologies is the integration of business logic and infrastructure ser- vices. In this paper, we investigate the current situation regarding transaction management services and discuss existing problems. We then present a concep- tual framework for a model-based transaction service configuration approach and explain its constituent parts. The framework is based on metamodelling and thus can directly be used for efficient development of tool support.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Maydl, Walter</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Design Accompanying Analysis of Component-Based Embedded Software</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>178-193</pages><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Maydl - 2004 - Design Accompanying Analysis of Component-Based Embedded Software(6).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;Germany;Innstr;University;University of Passau</label><abstract>Design accompanying analysis techniques for component- based embedded systems based on the dataflow paradigm are presented. The underlying signal model covers not only the value range and the time domain but also attributes of the signal data transport. Compo- nents are modelled as functions on streams of signal data. This allows to describe the behavior of dataflow components precisely by constraints. Static constraints, e.g., equality of sampling periods, may be as complex as multivariate polynomials and are enforced by a new interface type sys- tem. Dynamic constraints, e.g., describing communication protocols, are checked using a novel model checking technique based on fifo automata. The objective of these mathematically well-founded analysis techniques is to detect as many program errors as possible during design. Moreover, the component model is compositional resulting in well-defined hierarchi- cal abstraction. Alltogether, this results in a more reliable development of complex applications in a shorter design time.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Meyerh, Marcus</author><author>Neumann, Christoph</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>TESTEJB - A Measurement Framework for EJBs</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>294-301</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Meyerh, Neumann - 2004 - TESTEJB - A Measurement Framework for EJBs(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;Friedrich-Alexander University of Erlangen and Nue;Germany;University</label><abstract>Specification of Quality of Service (QoS) for components can only be done in relation to the QoS the components themselves are given by imported components. Developers as well as users need support in order to derive valid data for specification respectively for checking whether a selected component complies with its specification. In this paper we introduce the architecture of a measurement framework for EJBs giving such support and discuss in detail the measurement of the well understood property of response time.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mikic-Rakic, Marija</author><author>Medvidovic, Nenad</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Software Architectural Support for Disconnected Operation in Highly Distributed Environments</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>23-39</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Mikic-rakic, Medvidovic - 2004 - Software Architectural Support for Disconnected Operation in Highly Distributed Environments.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Computer Science Department;North America;USA;University;University of Southern California</label><abstract>In distributed and mobile environments, the connections among the hosts on which a software system is running are often unstable. As a result of connectivity losses, the overall availability of the system decreases. The distri- bution of software components onto hardware nodes (i.e., deployment architec- ture) may be ill-suited for the given target hardware environment and may need to be altered to improve the software system’s availability. The critical diffi- culty in achieving this task lies in the fact that determining a software system’s deployment that will maximize its availability is an exponentially complex problem. In this paper, we present an automated, flexible, software architecture- based solution for disconnected operation that increases the availability of the system during disconnection. We provide a fast approximative solution for the exponentially complex redeployment problem, and assess its performance.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Min, Hyun Gi</author><author>Choi, Si Won</author><author>Kim, Soo Dong</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Using Smart Connectors to Resolve Partial Matching Problems in COTS Component Acquisition</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>40-47</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Min, Choi, Kim - 2004 - Using Smart Connectors to Resolve Partial Matching Problems in COTS Component Acquisition(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Asia;Department of Computer Science;Korea;Soongsil University;University</label><abstract>Components, especially commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) compo- nents, are mainly for inter-organizational reuse. One of the essential tasks in component-based development (CBD) is to locate and reuse the right compo- nents that provide the functionality and interface required by component con- sumers. However, if a candidate component provides a limited applicability and customizability so that it does not completely satisfy the functionality and inter- face needed, then a component consumer cannot reuse the component in appli- cation development. We call it a partial matching problem in component acqui- sition. To resolve this problem, we propose smart connectors that fill the gap be- tween candidate components and the specification of components required. By using connectors, partially matched components become reusable in application development without sacrificing the component consumer’s requirements. Con- sequently, the effort and cost to develop new components and applications can be greatly reduced. In this paper, we propose four types of connectors, and each connector type is specified with its applicable situation and instructions to de- sign correct connectors.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mitchell, John C</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Proceedings Introduction</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Mitchell - 2004 - Lecture Notes in Computer Science(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Moller, Anders</author><author>Froberg, Joakim</author><author>Nolin, Mikael</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Industrial Requirements on Component Technologies for Embedded Systems</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>146-161</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Moller, Froberg, Nolin - 2004 - Industrial Requirements on Component Technologies for Embedded Systems(3).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;Malaga University;Malardalen Real-Time Research Centre;Private Company;Sweden;University;Volvo Construction Equipment</label><abstract>Software component technologies have not yet been generally accepted by embedded-systems industries. In order to better understand why this is the case, we present a set of requirements, based on industrial needs, that are deemed decisive for introducing a component technology. The requirements we present can be used to evaluate existing component technologies before introducing them in an industrial context. They can also be used to guide modifications and/or extensions to component tech- nologies, to make them better suited for industrial deployment. One of our findings is that a major source of requirements is non-technical in its nature. For a component technology to become a viable solution in an in- dustrial context, its impact on the overall development process needs to be addressed. This includes issues like component life-cycle management, and support for the ability to gradually migrate into the new technology</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Muskens, Johan</author><author>Chaudron, Michel</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Prediction of Run-Time Resource Consumption in Multi-task Component-Based Software Systems</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>162-177</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Muskens, Chaudron - 2004 - Prediction of Run-Time Resource Consumption in Multi-task Component-Based Software Systems(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Department of Mathematics and Computer Science Tec;Europe;The Netherlands;University</label><abstract>Embedded systems must be cost-effective. This imposes strict requirements on the resource consumption of their applications. It is therefore desirable to be able to determine the resource consump- tion of applications as early as possible in its development. Only then, a designer is able to guarantee that an application will fit on a target device. In this paper we will present a method for predicting run-time resource resource consumption in multi-task component based systems based on a design of an application. In [5] we describe a scenario based resource prediction technique and show that it can be applied to non-pre-emptive non-processing resources, like memory. In this paper we extend this tech- nique, which enables us to handle pre-emptive processing resources and their scheduling policies. Examples of these class of resources are CPU and network. For component based software engineering the challenge is to express re- source consumption characteristics per component, and to combine them to do predictions over compositions of components. To this end, we pro- pose a model and tools, for combining individual resource estimations of components. These composed resource estimations are then used in scenarios (which model run-time behavior) to predict resource consump- tion.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Nierstrasz, Oscar</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Putting Change at the Center of the Software Process</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>1-4</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Nierstrasz - 2004 - Putting Change at the Center of the Software Process(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Europe;Software Composition Group;Switzerland;University;University of Bern</label></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Norris, Boyana</author><author>Ray, Jaideep</author><author>Armstrong, Rob</author><author>Mcinnes, Lois C</author><author>Bernholdt, David E</author><author>Elwasif, Wael R</author><author>Malony, Allen D</author><author>Shende, Sameer</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Computational Quality of Service for Scientific Components</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>264-271</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Norris et al. - 2004 - Computational Quality of Service for Scientific Components(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Argonne;Argonne National Laboratory;Insitute;Livermore;North America;Oak Ridge National Laboratory;Sandia National Laboratiories;USA;University;University of Oregon</label><abstract>Scientific computing on massively parallel computers presents unique challenges to component-based software engineering (CBSE). While CBSE is at least as enabling for scientific computing as it is for other arenas, the requirements are different.We briefly discuss howthese requirements shape the Common Com- ponent Architecture, and we describe some recent research on quality-of-service issues to address the computational performance and accuracy of scientific simu- lations.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sandstrom, Kristian</author><author>Fredriksson, Johan</author><author>Akerholm, Mikael</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Introducing a Component Technology for Safety Critical Embedded Real-Time Systems</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>194-208</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Sandstrom, Fredriksson, Akerholm - 2004 - Introducing a Component Technology for Safety Critical Embedded Real-Time Systems(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Department of Computer Science and Engineering;Europe;Malardalen Real-Time Research Centre;Malardalen University;Sweden;University;Vasteras</label><abstract>Safety critical embedded real-time systems represent a class of systems that has attracted relatively little attention in research ad- dressing component based software engineering. Hence, the most widely spread component technologies are not used for resource constrained safety critical real-time systems. They are simply to resource demand- ing, to complex and to unpredictable. In this paper we show how to use component based software engineering for low footprint systems with very high demands on safe and reliable behaviour. The key concept is to provide expressive design time models and yet resource effective run- time models by statically resolve resource usage and timing by powerful compile time techniques. This results in a component technology for re- source effective and temporally verified mapping of a component model to a commercial real-time operating system</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shukla, Rakesh</author><author>Strooper, Paul</author><author>Carrington, David</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>A Framework for Reliability Assessment of Software Components</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>272-279</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Shukla, Strooper, Carrington - 2004 - A Framework for Reliability Assessment of Software Components(3).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Australia;School of Information Technology and Electrical En;The University of Queensland;University</label><abstract>This paper proposes a conceptual framework for the reliability as- sessment of software components that incorporates test case execution and out- put evaluation. Determining an operational profile and test output evaluation are two difficult and important problems that must be addressed in such a frame- work. Determining an operational profile is difficult, because it requires antici- pating the future use of the component. An expected result is needed for each test case to evaluate the test result and a test oracle is used to generate these ex- pected results. The framework combines statistical testing and test oracles im- plemented as self-checking versions of the implementations. The framework is illustrated using two examples that were chosen to identify the issues that must be addressed to provide tool support for the framework</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Simons, Kevin</author><author>Stafford, Judith</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>CMEH : Container Managed Exception Handling for Increased Assembly Robustness</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>122-129</pages><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Simons, Stafford - 2004 - CMEH Container Managed Exception Handling for Increased Assembly Robustness.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Department of Computer Science Tufts University;North America;USA;University</label><abstract>Component containers provide a deployment environment for com- ponents in a component-based system. Containers supply a variety of services to the components that are deployed in them, such as persistence, enforcement of security policies and transaction management. Recently, containers have shown a large amount of potential for aiding in the predictable assembly of component-based systems. This paper describes an augmentation to the compo- nent container, called the Container-Managed Exception Handling (CMEH) Framework, which provides an effective means for deploying exception han- dling mini-components into a component-based system. This framework pro- motes a more effective handling of exceptional events, as well as a better sepa- ration of concerns, yielding a more robust component assembly</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Taborda, Louis J M</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>The Release Matrox for Component-Based Software Systems</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>100-113</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Taborda - 2004 - The Release Matrox for Component-Based Software Systems(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Australia;Macquarie Graduate School of Management;Macquarie University;University</label><abstract>The challenge of managing the development and evolution of com- plex, component-based software is increasingly being recognized as the devel- opment of such systems becomes more common. This paper attempts to under- stand the relevance of current management best practices by utilizing a simple meta-model to illustrate the impact that architectural complexity and reusable components have on management patterns. The model serves as a heuristic de- vice and supports the view that products based on a framework of reusable software components pose new challenges and have to be managed simultane- ously at a number of different levels. This provides a rationale for the Release Matrix, a generalization of a software release plan, previously proposed as a technique for managing software product lines. The Release Matrix has practical applications for tracking the evolution of complex component-based systems and is shown via the model to be a natural consequence of increased architec- tural complexity and component reuse. This paper has relevance for developers seeking simple techniques to help them manage challenging component-based programs, as well as researchers interested in the conceptual basis and limits of current management practices.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tivoli, Massimo</author><author>Inverardi, Paola</author><author>Presutti, Valentina</author><author>Forghieri, Alessandro</author><author>Sebastianis, Maurizio</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Correct Components Assembly for a Product Data Management Cooperative System</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>84-99</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Tivoli et al. - 2004 - Correct Components Assembly for a Product Data Management Cooperative System(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Bologna;Europe;Italy;Private Company;Think3 company via Ronzani;University;University of Bologna Dip. Informatica;University of L’Aquila Dip. Informatica</label><abstract>In this paper we report on a case study of correct automatic assembly of software components. We show the application of our tool (called Synthesis) for correct components assembly to a software system in the area of CSCW (Computer Supported Cooperative Work). More specifically we consider a product data management (PDM) cooperative system which has been developed by the company Think3 in Bologna, ITALY (www.think3.com). In the area of CSCW, the automatic enforc- ing of desired interactions among the components forming the system requires the ability to properly manage the dynamic interactions of the components. Moreover once a customer acquires a CSCW system, the vendor of the CSCW system has to spend many further resources in order to integrate the CSCW system with the client applications used by the customer organization. Thus the full automation of the phase of integration code development has a great influence for a good setting of a CSCW system on the market. We present the application of our approach and we describe our experience in automatic derivation of the code which integrates the components forming the PDM cooperative sys- tem above mentioned. The case study we treat in this paper represent the first attempt to, successfully, apply Synthesis in real-scale contexts.</abstract></record><record><database name="2004.enl" path="2004.enl">2004.enl</database><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tyler, Benjamin</author><author>Soundarajan, Neelam</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Ivica Crnkovic, Judith A. Stafford, Heinz W. Schmidt and Kurt Wallnau</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Testing Framework Components</title><secondary-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Component-Based Software Engineering 7th International Symposium, CBSE</full-title></periodical><pages>138-145</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><pub-location>Edinburgh, UK</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Tyler, Soundarajan - 2004 - Testing Framework Components(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><label>Columbus;Computer and Information Science;North America;Ohio State University;USA;University</label><abstract>An object-oriented framework can be a key component in building products for a given application area.An application developer need only provide definitions suited to the needs of the particular application for the hook methods. With appropriate initializations, the calls to thehookmethodsmadebythe template methods defined in the framework will be dispatched to the definitions provided by the application developer, thus customizing the behavior of the template methods. Specifying and testing such frameworks present some challenges;wediscuss these and develop ways to address them.</abstract></record></records></xml>
